hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the TS automation
playlist so today I'm going to talk
about a common issue which people face
especially when they are new to tosa or
they are working in a project uh and
they are using a multi-user workspace
which has got a common repository now in
these kind of projects you will come
across scenarios when there will be
folders or there will be objects which
you are not able to access even though
um I have done an update all which means
all the objects are already updated uh
from uh the repository so I have got the
latest changes here in my current
workspace but still I'm not able to
access some objects for example this
vehicle insurance folder it looks like a
common component folder but actually it
is grade out okay and also the objects
inside these uh folder component folder
are also grade out okay and there you
can see there is a cloud sign here for
configurations and test events so when I
click on these configurations and test
events uh they get somehow enabled for
me but the remaining are still showing
as disabled right and if I right click
on this and go to the context menu I
don't see a checkout option the checkout
option is cre out okay now if you notice
there's also another option which is the
checkout tree option which seems to be
enabled so let's go ahead and try this
so when I click on on this you will see
that tosa will tell me that there are no
objects to check out but I have got lots
of objects which are currently not
accessible to me so why TOA is telling
me that there are no objects to check
out so why it is like this and what's
the solution for this because I cannot
access this folder so I cannot create
any object inside this I cannot edit it
or I cannot check it out right so
basically this folder is inaccessible to
me even though I am working um in a
workspace which is connected to the
correct repository and I have already
done an update all
okay now first uh let's understand what
is the reason for this Okay the reason
for this is this folder and all of its
object are currently excluded from
synchronization now what is
synchronization so synchronization is a
process where all the objects from your
current workspace is synchronized With
The Changes uh made in the repository
okay so the repository and the workspace
will um synchronize all the changes so
your local workspace will be up to date
with the repository changes okay but um
if you're are working in a project so
sometimes some folders will be excluded
from ionization and that is done on
purpose especially for large workspaces
where you have got lots and lots of
objects this is to um make the workspace
more efficient because the processing
time will increase if you have got lots
of objects to synchronize every time you
open a new workspace and that is why
some of the folders are excluded from
synchronization so that it can save uh
some time for the automation testers
when they are opening the workspace and
they will include only the folders which
are required for their own work and they
will include them for synchronization if
they are not already synchronized okay
but initially these folders will be
inaccessible for them so the solution
for this is simply go to that particular
object and just uh do either select
include all necessary items for tree or
select include for
synchronization okay so when you select
this particular option so what tosa will
do is it will include that particular
object for synchronization and then it
will synchronize it with the common
repository okay so now this particular
folder will be
accessible so uh this is how you can uh
include uh your objects for
synchronization if you want to exclude
any particular object for
synchronization then this is the the
option okay so you can right click on
that particular object and exclude from
synchronization you can also exclude the
tree from synchronization which means
the parent object and all the child
objects are also excluded okay so if I
now select this you will see that the ex
execution folder will be grade out okay
so next time when I check in this
particular object will not be
synchronized with the common Repository
okay and that's what is meant by um
exclude uh from synchronization uh you
can also exclude the tree from
synchronization and what that will do is
it will exclude all the child objects
from the synchronization and everything
will be grade out
okay now uh there are a few other things
also um like if you go to any particular
object and if you check it out okay then
in the property section you will find a
property whose name is synchronization
policy Now by default all the objects
are set to this particular value which
is customizable default is on which
means uh by default all the objects are
included for
synchronization okay but um you can also
set this off which means it will not be
uh included for synchronization you can
also set it to cannot be excluded which
means means um anybody cannot just
exclude that folder for synchronization
or object for synchronization and also
you can choose this option which is
cannot be excluded for whole tree which
means all the child objects can also not
be excluded from
synchronization okay so all of these
different options you can choose
whenever you are creating uh new object
in your project um depending on the
situation and depending on what you want
to you can select any of these options
but when you um export or import any
particular objects then um it is reset
back to this particular uh property
value which is customizable default is
on okay also if um the customizable
default is on for one particular object
then all the child objects which you
create under that object will also get
the same value which is set for the
parent object okay
so this is how you can set different
synchronization policy and uh this is a
common issue as I said especially with
uh newcomers who are new to tosa or who
are just starting to work uh in their
respective projects who are working on a
multi-user workspace which is connected
to a common repository so this issue is
very common and very frequently um
occurred and that's why I thought I
would talk about this so that you are
aware of this particular problem and you
know why it happens and also what is the
workaround for
this that's all for this particular
video if you have any questions then
please leave it in the comments if you
like this video then please subscribe to
our Channel thanks for watching and I
will see you in the next video